topnonprofits.com 2017-06-22

# Privacy Policy - Top Nonprofits

_**Your privacy is critically important to us. At Top Nonprofits we have a few fundamental principles:**_

  * We don’t ask you for personal information unless we truly need it. (We can’t stand services that ask you for things like your gender or income level for no apparent reason.)
  * We don’t share your personal information with anyone except to comply with the law or protect our rights.
  * We don’t store personal information on our servers unless required for the on-going operation of one of our services.
  * We aim to make it as simple as possible for you to control what’s visible to the public, seen by search engines, kept private, and permanently deleted.

Below is our privacy policy which incorporates these goals:[](http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/2.5/) (Note, we’ve decided to make this privacy policy available under a  **Creative Commons Sharealike**  license, which means you’re more than welcome to steal it and repurpose it for your own use, just make sure to replace references to us with ones to you, and if you want we’d appreciate a link somewhere on your site to [TopNonprofits.com](https://topnonprofits.com/) and [Automattic.com](http://automattic.com/) (whose similarly licensed privacy policy was used to build this one).

If you have questions about deleting or correcting your personal data please contact our [support team](mailto:craig@topnonprofits.com).

Top Nonprofits LLC. (“ **Top Nonprofits** ”) operates TopNonprofits.com. It is Top Nonprofits’ policy to respect your privacy regarding any information we may collect while operating our website.

**Website Visitors**

Like most website operators, Top Nonprofits collects non-personally-identifying information of the sort that web browsers and servers typically make available, such as the browser type, language preference, referring site, and the date and time of each visitor request. Top Nonprofits’ purpose in collecting non-personally identifying information is to better understand how Top Nonprofits’ visitors use its website. From time to time, Top Nonprofits may release non-personally-identifying information in the aggregate, e.g., by publishing a report on trends in the usage of its website.

Top Nonprofits also collects potentially personally-identifying information like Internet Protocol (IP) addresses for logged in users and for users leaving comments. Top Nonprofits only discloses logged in user and commenter IP addresses under the same circumstances that it uses and discloses personally-identifying information as described below, except that blog commenter IP addresses are visible and disclosed to the administrators of the blog where the comment was left.

**Gathering of Personally-Identifying Information**

Certain visitors to Top Nonprofits’ website choose to interact with Top Nonprofits in ways that require Top Nonprofits to gather personally-identifying information. The amount and type of information that Top Nonprofits gathers depends on the nature of the interaction. Those who engage in transactions with Top Nonprofits are asked to provide additional information, including as necessary the personal and financial information required to process those transactions. In each case, Top Nonprofits collects such information only insofar as is necessary or appropriate to fulfill the purpose of the visitor’s interaction with Top Nonprofits. Top Nonprofits does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below. And visitors can always refuse to supply personally-identifying information, with the caveat that it may prevent them from engaging in certain website-related activities.

**Aggregated Statistics**

Top Nonprofits may collect statistics about the behavior of visitors to its website. For instance, Top Nonprofits may monitor the most popular posts on TopNonprofits.com and may display this information publicly or provide it to others. However, Top Nonprofits does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below.

**Protection of Certain Personally-Identifying Information**

Top Nonprofits discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only to those of its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations that (i) need to know that information in order to process it on Top Nonprofits’ behalf or to provide services available at Top Nonprofits’ website, and (ii) that have agreed not to disclose it to others. Top Nonprofits’ will not rent or sell potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information to anyone. Other than to its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations, as described above, Top Nonprofits discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only in response to a subpoena, court order or other governmental request, or when Top Nonprofits believes in good faith that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect the property or rights of Top Nonprofits, third parties or the public at large. Top Nonprofits takes all measures reasonably necessary to protect against the unauthorized access, use, alteration or destruction of potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information.

**Cookies**

A cookie is a string of information that a website stores on a visitor’s computer, and that the visitor’s browser provides to the website each time the visitor returns. Top Nonprofits uses cookies to help Top Nonprofits identify and track visitors, their usage of Top Nonprofits website, and their website access preferences. Top Nonprofits visitors who do not wish to have cookies placed on their computers should set their browsers to refuse cookies before using Top Nonprofits’ website, with the drawback that certain features of Top Nonprofits’ website may not function properly without the aid of cookies.

**Business Transfers**

If Top Nonprofits, or substantially all of its assets were acquired, or in the unlikely event that Top Nonprofits goes out of business or enters bankruptcy, user information would be one of the assets that is transferred or acquired by a third party. You acknowledge that such transfers may occur, and that any acquirer of Top Nonprofits may continue to use your personal information as set forth in this policy.

**Ads**

Ads appearing on any of our website may be delivered to users by advertising partners, who may set cookies. These cookies allow the ad server to recognize your computer each time they send you an online advertisement to compile information about you or others who use your computer. This information allows ad networks to, among other things, deliver targeted advertisements that they believe will be of most interest to you. This Privacy Policy covers the use of cookies by Top Nonprofits and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers.

**Privacy Policy Changes**

Although most changes are likely to be minor, Top Nonprofits may change its Privacy Policy from time to time, and in Top Nonprofits’ sole discretion. Top Nonprofits encourages visitors to frequently check this page for any changes to its Privacy Policy. Your continued use of this site after any change in this Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of such change.

**Change log:**

No changes to date.
